# **Pankaj Kumar Jangid**

## **Senior Android Developer**

D.O.B.: 16-Jan-1990 Nationality: India

Location: Jaipur, Rajasthan Mobile: +91 9784632484 Passport No: P5532096 Email: pankai0619@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pankajjangid

Website: <a href="http://pankajjangid.com/">http://pankajjangid.com/</a>



#### **PROFILE**

Pankaj Kumar Jangid is an accomplished Application Development with 6 years of experience as an Android Application Developer. I am good at designing, implementing, integrating, testing, and supporting impactful applications developed in diverse, collaborative environments for mobile and tablet devices on the Android platform.

#### **EDUCATION**

Rajasthan Technical University, Kota (Raj) M.C.A 2014 Rajasthan University, Jaipur (Raj) B.C.A, 2011

#### SPECIALIZED SKILLS

- Native Android Development both java and Kotlin.
- Experience in MVC, MVP, MVVM, and VIPER architecture.
- Create UI using Material Design as per Google guidelines.
- Jetpack, Localization, AndroidX, XML & JSON, Lottie, Google Firebase, and Third-Parties Libraries.
- Augmented reality like Wikitude SDK integration
- Payment gateway integration like Braintree, Stripe, Paypal, etc.
- Knowledge about flutter & Dart.
- Good knowledge of Agile development, Jira, Slack, Git, Github, SVN and Bitbucket, Atlassian, Agile
- Good knowledge of Dependency injection Framework (Kodein, Koin, Dagger).

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Senior Software Engineer (Android),** Dew Solutions Private Limited (Oct 2021- Till now) Gurugram, Haryana 122018

#### Key Responsibility:

- Develop new features for **Decathlon India** Home Page and Search Screen.
- Revamp the UI & Functionality Search screen which gives 30% more user interactions.
- Working on the agile environment.
- Write Unit tests & Resolve the Bugs.
- Develop scalable Android Applications.

## **Android Developer,** CMS COMPUTERS LTD. (June 2020- Oct 2021)

Jaipur, Rajasthan 302019

Key Responsibility:

- Maintaining the existing code and developing new features for Rajasthan Police Project CCTNS Android Applications.
- Creating a flutter application from the scratch.
- Building compliant and scalable android Applications.

## **Android Developer,** Octal IT Solution (May 2018- May 2020)

Jaipur, Rajasthan 302017

Key Responsibility:

- Contributed to the full mobile application development lifecycle from planning, requirement gathering, development, testing, and launching on Google play store for beta testing.
- Development, testing, deployment, and code enhancement.
- Communication with the clients (US, UK, UAE, Singapore).
- Responsible for the development of all application components and UI resources.
- Building compliant and scalable android Applications.
- Worked with the UI team to design the appropriate icon and display for the screens.

# **Android Developer,** RAD Techno Solution Pvt. Ltd (Mar 2016 – Apr 2018)

Jaipur, Rajasthan 302020

Key Responsibility:

- Participate in complete Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) for proper analysis, development, testing, deployment, and code enhancement.
- Responsible for the development of all application components and UI resources

#### **PORTFOLIO**

You can check the portfolio of all projects on the website.

# https://github.com/pankajjangid/Portfolio

Project Name: Decathlon Online Shopping App

Description: Now enjoy and experience the entire offering of Decathlon India's 70+ sports and over 5,000 products by using the Decathlon mobile application!

Play Store Link:https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.evamall.evacustomer&hl=en\_IN

Project Name: RajCop (Only For Rajasthan Police Officials)

Description: RajCop - Mobile application only to be used by authorized Rajasthan Police Officials. Others may not install and try it out. Its use is subject to legal consequences.

Play Store Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.datainfosys.rajasthanpolice.official

Project Name: RajCop Citizen

Description: Lockdown Pass(Restrictions related to Corona Virus spread).

Play Store Link: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.datainfosys.rajasthanpolice.publicapp">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.datainfosys.rajasthanpolice.publicapp</a>

Project Name: Voila SG

Description: Our objective is to provide an efficient housekeeping service to a satisfactory standard.

Play Store Link: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.voila.supervisor">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.voila.supervisor</a>

Project Name: Voila Helper

Description: Our objective is to provide an efficient housekeeping service to a satisfactory standard.

Play Store Link: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.octal.voila">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.octal.voila</a>

Project Name: Yogapp

Description: Find a variety of qualified yoga teachers near you. Review detailed teacher profiles and ratings

Play Store Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yoga.student

Project Name: iGuruJi -CSIR NET, GATE, IIT-JAM

Description: iGuruJi.in is an android Test Prep and video portal owned by AADHAR INSTITUTE

Play Store Link: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.iguruji.biolifescience">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.iguruji.biolifescience</a>

## **LANGUAGES**

**English** – Excellent reading, writing and speaking **Hindi** – Excellent reading, writing, and speaking

# **OTHER INTERESTS**

Listening to podcasts, Weight lifting, diet & nutrition

**THANKS** 

Pankaj Kumar Jangid